Savina comes here because she has a thing for Luciano.
I suppose it's the pastime of a widow with time and money on her hands.
I guess.
She used to be a violinist.
Be careful around the steam.
That beautiful woman?
Luciano pretends he doesn't notice.
Man, what a waste.
Maybe he plans to stay alone forever.
That's not it at all, I bet.
It's because he still loves his late wife.
You too?
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
Here.
Hmm?
I'm going to be in a concert.
You know how to play an instrument?
It's nothing special.
There will be a bunch of ensembles performing.
Oh?
What?
I'm going to be busy with rehearsals until the concert,
so...
You aren't bored?
Not at all.
I told you to stay quiet, in the back.
His mother is busy, so we don't have an option.
Franci's a good boy, so we're happy to have him.
Want something to eat?
Sure.
It's so good.
Signore.
Yes?
I'd like to extend you an invitation.
I'm directing a group of children in a concert next week.
It's next Wednesday.
I do believe this restaurant is closed that day.
I'd be delighted if you accompanied me.
You're single, aren't you?
I got some info on you from the other camerieres.
What do you say?
I'm sorry.
I have a previous engagement.
I see.
I'm envious of her.
Take her to the show, if you want.
Goodbye.
Oh crap!
For her to give him the tickets instead...
Papa, I'll leave the tickets I mentioned here.
OK.
I've been busy and don't have time to look after him.
I'm really grateful you're taking care of him.
Don't thank me.
Why don't we go get dinner sometime?
The three of you should take your time.
Franci, I'll make you a tasty snack.
Come to the kitchen.
Sure.
Ah. Nonno had the same tickets.
What?
Really?
He gets asked out too.
He's still young. There are plenty of good women for him.
Oh?
What are you talking about?
It's been quite some time since your wife passed away.
She figured you might be lonely, so came over the house,
but I...
We all need love until the day we die.
That goes for men and women.
What?
I'm kinda envious of Savina.
She's pretty and passionate...
I think she's really serious about you.
I think going on a date every once in a while isn't a bad thing...
How about you go on some dates yourself?
I'm getting impatient with you.
I'm trying...
Come here.
Huh?
Tickets to a classical concert.
But these...
I've got tickets already.
Don't do something tactless like going with another woman.
What?
Yes, that one.
Please let the other party know it's all settled.
Yes. OK, then.
I'm counting on you.
It's nothing.
Yeah.
Bye. Ciao.
I'll help you carry these.
Claudio!
Thank you.
This is it.
What are you doing? Come in.
Oh, right.
Put the groceries down there.
Well, I guess I'll get...
I'll put a pot of coffee on.
I won't, if you're in a rush, though.
One cup never hurt anyone.
Have a seat.
Some of those things must bring back memories for you.
It's rude of me to look through your things.
Not at all! We used to be married!
That's just like you to say that, though.
You haven't changed, not one bit.
To our new lives.
Salute.
Say, isn't that the sweater I bought for you?
You don't wear it much, so I thought you didn't like it.
I was trying to take good care of it.
It's a valuable keepsake.
Gabrielle...
Yes, let me get a good look at your face.
Being with you makes me want to get in trouble.
I should get going. We weren't married long, but I enjoyed it.
Ciao.
Take care.
How's my coffee?
It's good.
You made me coffee every morning.
It was delicate and hot.
I was grateful for each morning.
Huh?
I don't think I ever told you that when we were living together, though.
It's strange. Now that we're broken up,
I can say it.
Thank you. Bye.
Thanks for having me.
What's wrong, Nicoletta?
Claudio seems depressed.
Is that so?
Something happened to him, huh?
You think so, too?
If you aren't feeling well...
No, I'm fine.
We're both single. You don't have to be shy with me.
I appreciate that.
So, you plan to live alone forever, Luciano?
Hmm?
Sorry, I shouldn't have asked that.
How about you?
I...
I lost my life partner. You're in a different situation.
Time stops for the dead.
But if you go on living, things change.
Whether or not you ask for it, the clock keeps ticking.
Claudio...
Yes?
Umm, err...
I...
Umm...
Err...
Claudio!
I'll always make time for you!
Huh?
If you ever need to talk about something that troubles you,
come running to my chest!
I don't mean anything weird by that!
Oh, I know.
Thank you.
Because we're friends, after all.
That we are.
I don't think Claudio will turn me down, but...
Take her to the show, if you want.
I don't think I'll ever be as sleek as Savina...
That was pretty good.
OK, I'll be back.
Have fun.
Signore Cameriere.
That previous engagement... Was it with your grandson?
I was asked to watch him.
Oh dear. Here I was wondering what your lovely wife was like.
I'm relieved.
Looks like I am without a rival.
Or am I mistaken?
Is there?
Come here.
Thanks for watching him today, Papa.
Huh? Savina!
Hello.
Do you know each other?
Yes.
She's a regular at the restaurant.
Wow, what a coincidence.
This is Nicoletta and Marina.
Nicoletta works in the kitchen at dell'orso.
Marina is Vito the cameriere's wife.
Nice to meet you.
Sorry for coming with a woman.
Savina is the wife of the owner of the studio I attend.
She used to be a violinist, so she gives me lessons sometimes.
What? "Wife"?
Huh? She has a husband? That means...
It was a beautiful performance.
Thank you, Savina.
What?!
We should get going.
Ciao.
You knew I was married, didn't you?
I must have behaved differently from a widow, huh?
How was it? Did you enjoy yourself?
I did.
You didn't fall asleep like Franci, did you?
Of course not.
Hey, was the person who invited you there?
Was Mamma always with you?
You have to wrap up now, right?
I'll take Francesco home, so just come get him tomorrow.
Thank you. I'll be over first thing in the morning.
I'm going this way, too.
Ciao.
How many years ago did Luciano's wife pass away?
Nine years ago. Right after I found out I was pregnant with Franci.
I'd think she was my Mamma being reborn, had Franci been a girl.
But, I'm glad I had a boy.
No one could take the place of my Mamma.
Or Franci, for that matter.
I've thought it would be good for him if he met someone, but...
But he's still in love with his wife, huh?
Savina never came to the restaurant after that.
No one knows what happened to her adulterous feelings.
Secret love...
Requited love...
Both of them cause their share of problems.
But I guess they both can be called love.
Love takes all shapes and sizes.
It's not that he can't forget,
it's that he doesn't want to forget, no?
Claudio!