His birthday's
coming soon, isn't it?
I get uneasy every time
I look at the calendar.
But, my husband...
If he has to work,
he has to work.
He couldn't make it
last year, either.
Franci is always
so disappointed.
It'll be fine.
I'll make sure of it.
You want one of the cakes
you usually get?
Yes, but give me
the largest one you've got.
Sounds like quite the gathering this year. That's fantastic.
He's turning nine already.
I'm going to
make it a fun day.
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
This is great. I've always wanted the three of us to drink together.
And, I had no idea that Luciano had such a lovely daughter.
I thought about
introducing myself to you.
Papa told me so much
about you, Nicoletta.
He probably said things like, "This newbie
who just barged in one day," huh?
He means well when he says those things, though. Please forgive him.
Means well, huh?
All right, since we're off tomorrow,
let's get another bottle!
I'm can't, I have
a date tonight.
Where you headed?
We're just going to
jog home together.
You guys are like
two peas in a pod.
A date, huh?
I want to go on
a date someday.
I should get going too.
What?
It's Franci's
birthday tomorrow.
I've got to prepare.
Oh, I had no idea!
Congrats!
Nonno is going all out.
Since my husband can't make it,
he's working extra hard on the festivities.
That's a side of him
that he'll never show us.
I'd like to see it, though.
Say, would you mind
if I stopped by?
I'd love for you to come!
But are you sure you'd want to use your day off for that?
Sure! How about you, Marina?
If you're okay with
an adult guest coming...
Splendid. Franci will
be so happy.
Oh, but we
can't tell Luciano...
Good night.
Ciao.
Ciao, Luciano, Margherita.
Ciao, Margherita, Nicoletta.
So... We can make it a real surprise party for Luciano.
What do you say?
Luciano will be
totally surprised.
Sure, sounds like fun.
I'm all for it, of course.
And you, Teo?
My plans fell apart,
so since I'm free...
Gigi?
So it's a yes from you, too.
Thanks, everyone!
You've really gotten
to know us well, Nicoletta.
The fact you can understand what Gigi is thinking
means you've matured as an apprentice.
Is that a good thing?
Papa came back to get
something he forgot.
I think I left it on top
of Teo's motorcycle.
There it is.
I know you've all got the day off,
but don't go drinking yourselves silly now.
Oh, do you have any particular plans tomorrow, Luciano?
It's a secret.
Then so are my plans.
Good night.
Thanks for
walking me home.
I'll try to get there
early tomorrow.
Francesco's friends will be arriving around five, right?
So I'll try to get
there around three...
I'm sorry, Papa! I'm doing something in the afternoon.
Huh?
Can you come
at around five, too?
At five? But then...
I can take care of the preparations by myself. I'll be fine.
You're on cake duty.
Don't be late.
I'm counting on you.
Good night!
Ciao.
Look at this!
Nice. Do you think
this will be okay here?
Yeah, it looks great.
So, how many people
are we expecting?
Fifteen, if you count
the adult guests.
Did you hear that? Can you handle all that by yourself?
Wanna have a contest? See who has the larger lung capacity?
Holy cow.
So Franci likes pizza, huh?
Yup, he'd eat it for breakfast, lunch, and dinner, if he could.
All right, ready to do this?
Yeah.
Oh, what about Gigi?
He's doing a... juice tasting?
That's too boring.
He'd like it, but he
won't be surprised by it.
Welcome home, Franci.
Welcome back.
Oh, the birthday
boy is here!
Want me to help
with something?
The birthday boy
shouldn't work.
Okay, Mamma.
I'll carry that!
Be careful. It's hot.
They look so good...
Ow!
Are you all right, Franci?
The cookies...
Oh, thank heavens.
What'll I do
with you, Franci?
Teo's got more cookies in the oven,
so don't worry about it.
Franci...
It's so nice out.
It's supposed to get
chilly tonight, though.
Wow, it's so cute.
It'd look good
on you, Nicoletta.
You think so?
Oh, that one would look
good on you, Claudio.
Oh, that's my favorite color.
Seriously?
Yeah.
This kinda feels like a date.
Well, should we get going?
Oh... Sure.
Grazie.
Prego.
We don't have
to go back yet?
Nah, we can kill a little more
time around here first.
Leave the party preparation
to the common folk.
Today is the prince's
birthday celebration!
But keep it secret
from Nonno.
Exactly. Secret.
Move!
What?
What was that
all about, Claudio?
Shh. Over there.
Huh?
Franci, stay in there!
Franci!
Nicoletta, move further in.
By the skin of our teeth.
Oh, right. I'll pick
up the cake.
Then so are my plans.
Oh, I see.
Hey, bro, isn't today Franci's festa?
Shouldn't you be going?
I was just stopping by for a bit.
Oh, then please give
Franci my present.
And tell him I apologize for
not being able to take off work.
Okay.
Our secret plan
was almost exposed.
It's a good thing
he didn't spot us.
Why did Luciano
go into that shop?
Nonna loved that bakery.
Nonna?
His late wife.
Oh, I see.
So, she liked that cake...
What was she like?
She was beautiful.
But we never met.
Hmm?
There are pictures
of her in Luciano's house.
She had a radiant smile.
Nonno is always
looking at photos of her.
I see.
Till death do us part... huh?
She used to always ask for a large cake because it was a "special occasion."
Festivals, weddings, birthdays...
She would just make them up
so she could eat it.
Well, congratulations on your grandson turning nine.
Grazie.
Wow!
Is everything to
your liking, young prince?
Yeah!
Come now,
let's get you changed.
Sure, Mamma.
Buonasera!
Buonasera.
Welcome.
We got here a little early.
Buonasera.
Have a seat. I'll bring you
something to drink.
Grazie.
You have so many butlers.
They're friends of Nonno. They're just helping out today.
It smells so good!
Buonasera. We've been
expecting you.
Nonna!
I'll be on camera duty.
I'll take care of the video.
Thanks, guys.
Oh, it's Papa.
Buonasera, Luciano.
That's the cake, isn't it?
I'll take it for you.
Buonasera, Luciano.
Please, allow me
to take your things.
Buonasera, Papa.
You were the ones that
plotted this, weren't you?
I'd prefer if
you said "planned".
Nonno!
This is a present
from your uncle.
I'll have to go
say thanks later.
Buon compleanno!
Happy birthday, Francesco!
It's delicious.
This is awesome, Franci.
What a great festa.
Yeah.
Tanti auguri a te,
tanti auguri a te...
Tanti auguri, Francesco.
Tanti auguri a te!
Blow out the candles, Franci!
Sorry, guys. Just wait
a little bit longer.
All yours.
You got it.
It's Teo's special dolce plate!
It's so pretty!
The dolce looks fantastic.
Incredible!
It's so good.
You've done enough.
Go take a break.
Very well.
We shall do just that.
Grazie.
Nicoletta?
I just needed some
fresh air to sober up.
Umm, this afternoon...
The party turned out
pretty nice, didn't it?
It sure did.
Franci.
Mamma.
Having a good time?
Yeah.
It's because Nonno
works in that restaurant.
Yeah, you're right.
Grazie, Nonno.
Hey.
Eat it.