Enjoy.
Thank you.
I made it a little strong,
because you seem tired.
Is that all right?
You read me like
a book. It’s delicious.
I’m glad I didn’t
bring an umbrella.
It gives me an excuse
to stay a while.
That’s true.
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
Huh?
Is there a special
guest coming tonight?
A certain someone from the past is coming with the owner and his wife tonight.
Oh?
Say, what is “Teo’s Specially-made Dolce Piatto” exactly?
Well, he’s not much for
Teo’s dolce, actually.
Buonasera.
Well, it’s been
a while, Claudio.
We’ve been
expecting you, Marzio.
The owner and his wife
haven’t arrived yet.
You all look well.
I hear about the restaurant
here and there.
Have you lost weight?
That’s because Gigi and I used to eat a ton, back then.
Speaking of Gigi…
He hasn’t changed a bit.
Eating as always.
Who is that?
Are you sure, Gigi?
Huh? Isn’t that one of the
really expensive bottles?
Who is that man?
Ah!
Nicoletta, come out here.
But I promised not
to leave the kitchen…
Today’s a special occasion.
Come on, introduce yourself
to your predecessor.
It’s a pleasure to
meet you. I’m Nicoletta.
I’m Marzio.
Looks like you’ve hired another cute, young lady again, huh?
He used to help
in the kitchen.
Besides Gigi, he’s been in the business longer than anyone.
Dell’orso has quite the past.
4 years prior
You overworked yourself.
Should I call your folks?
It’s okay.
After you’re discharged tomorrow,
want to stop for a drink on the way home?
You know, at the
bar where he works.
Yeah… okay. Let’s do that.
I’m feeling better already.
Buonasera.
Where’s that man?
That older barista.
Oh, my brother-in-law? He hasn’t worked here since last week.
What?
What? He quit?!
Really?
Ah, I get it. That’s why you came along to get me, Gigi.
And wearing a suit
on your day off…
I used to spend my days, waiting for work to get out, so I could go there.
There are plenty of
gentlemen in town,
but a place where you can have a drink and truly be at ease is rare indeed.
Would that be strange?
There’s still that
cameriere left…
What about the barista
from that bar?
Yeah, I had the same thought,
so I got his name and phone number.
Luciano De Luca…
I’m afraid I’ll have to pass.
I just grew tired of working
as a barista, so I quit.
I don’t think I can go back
to working the late shift…
Quit? Didn’t you just use your sick days to spend some time with your grandson?
But still, it’s a
great opportunity.
You’re more suited to being
a cameriere than a barista, I bet.
You stay out of this.
There are plenty of young men who can be camerieres.
Why would you want
someone like me?
To be honest,
it’s for my wife.
For your wife?
She’s got what you’d
call peculiar tastes…
We’ve been planning on opening the ristorante for months,
but she collapsed the
other day, from overworking.
So, I’d like to do
something for her.
I’ll introduce you
to someone else.
Just accept that
and go, please.
He’s a gentleman.
How can I put it…
A real man.
I’ve been working at
a ristorante outside of Rome.
I’ve been there
about twenty years.
Twenty years, you say?
The owner there has
been very generous to me,
but he passed
away recently…
The new owner doesn’t
take as kindly to me…
I’m sure he knows
what I’m referring to.
I heard you used to
work together…
He’s a brilliant man.
He’s incredibly sophisticated…
But, he had to quit
when his wife got sick.
So, I’m sure he’ll sympathize with the emotions you have towards your wife.
I’d love for him
to work for me.
Say no more.
I’ll convince him for you.
Thank you.
But, what about yourself?
I’d like to mull it
over a bit more.
I’ve worked at the same
place for a long time.
Of course.
We convinced each other.
Some Orsini wine
was involved.
Thank you both.
However, there’s that
sign out back…
Seeking bespectacled men,
fifty or older…
Just saw this, guys.
What do you say?
Oh.
Forgive my attire.
I was out for a jog.
Let me get my spectacles.
I’ve got no experience
as a cameriere,
but I’ve worked
plenty of different jobs.
As a concierge in a hotel, etc.
I’d love to try and
work as a cameriere.
He looks like a nice guy.
Indeed.
Allow me to introduce you all once again. This is an old associate of mine, Marzio.
He used to help out in the kitchen sometimes, when I ran the restaurant next to the winery.
These are the chefs,
Vanna and Dario.
They’re both masters
in the kitchen.
Claudio, a cameriere.
Also, Luciano and Vito.
These are the gentlemen who will manage the floor.
They’re all old men.
Seriously.
And this is Gigi,
our sommelier.
This is the wine list.
This is the food menu.
I’ll switch it up seasonly,
but we’ll start with this.
Oh, right.
They all wear spectacles.
It’s no big deal.
Don’t worry about it.
I hope this puts
a smile on her face.
The owner and his wife
sure are late, huh?
He told me to get
here before it opens.
I’m hungry, Grandpa.
Just a little longer, dear.
I’m sure she’s still
at work… My goodness.
Buonasera.
I’ll take your coats.
Right this way.
How about you bring out a little
of the food they make for the staff?
Not a problem.
We’ll move you to your table when the owner and his wife show up.
Nicoletta, keep them
company in their place.
Huh? But…
I’ll let the kitchen
staff know.
Th-Thank you.
The dinner service
won’t hit its peak for a bit.
Also, part of your job is to learn the restaurant’s history.
Eat up.
Twenty years already…
That’s so cool.
I’ve got to work
my hardest, too.
There’s so much about
Claudio I don’t know.
4 years prior
Being invited in before it even opens… I’m so excited!
I wonder what the
ristorante will be like.
I made special reservations. Let’s just take our time and enjoy ourselves.
Bear Street…
This is it, huh?
Ristorante casetta dell’orso.
Madam, will it be
to your liking?
I won’t pull any punches.
Buonasera.
B-Buonasera.
Allow me to take your shawl.
Grazie.
Right this way.
It’s beautiful.
Want to relax a little more?
Yes.
Order anything
on the menu.
I wonder what
I should get…
Here is the menu.
We’ve prepared a special menu to pair with the Orsini wine that you like so much.
I’m delighted.
What does that entail?
Allow me.
Yes, it includes
seasonal mushrooms.
We’ll be serving porcini
mushrooms tonight.
H-He’s a complete gentleman…
And he’s wearing spectacles!
Eggplant is in season now.
We’ll be including it
in tonight’s antipasto.
I cannot fathom another
restaurant this wonderful.
Both the food and
wine are delectable,
and so is the scenery!
You know, I’d like
to meet the chef, too.
Sure she won’t mind the fact that I’m not a gentleman?
It’s fine, fine.
I’m just the sous-chef.
Dario?
Everyone who works
here is older!
That’s wonderful!
I’ll revisit this situation
when I’m an older man.
So, do you like it?
I…
More than anything else…
The fact that you thought of me this much makes me so happy, Lorenzo!
It was a splendid evening.
Wow, I had no idea.
Oh, I see you told her
about that night.
When I saw the two
of them that night,
I just knew.
I knew I’d love this place
for a long time to come.
This restaurant’s origins go back to the owner’s deep love for his wife.
Yeah.
Be that as it may,
they sure are late.
Buonasera.
I got here as
quickly as I could.
It appears he’s arrived.
I’m so sorry to
keep you waiting.
Olga wanted to
give this to you.
She couldn’t break away
from work. I apologize.
I’ll catch her
next time, then.
Come on, let me buy
you a drink, Lorenzo.
Sure. That’s a fantastic idea.
She is such a bad person.
You planning on taking
the whole night off?
I was just on my way
back to the kitchen!
Get to work.
I will! I’ll work
for twenty years!
You worked late tonight.
Sorry, it was so hectic today.
Let’s invite Marzio out
the next chance we get.
We can have him join us at the end of the day, like this.
Seeing you smile
cleanses my soul.
Grazie.
Prego.
We’re not involved
in their feud,
so let’s stay on
good terms, Gigi.