I guess it's time
to go and try it...
Your food for the staff.
Knock it off already.
I'm not ready to serve it
to the owner yet.
Stop at a good point.
Staying up late is bad
for your complexion.
Right...
All right, this looks
like a cinch to make.
Was that pot there before?
Sure feels good
to do a nice deed.
It was her...
Every once in a while she does something that reminds me she's my mother.
What's that?
I totally forgot that her
birthday's coming up.
We had a party for her
here last year too.
Did you receive
an invitation?
Not at all.
It makes sense, though.
Since she doesn't want the owner to know
that I'm actually her daughter.
I guess she had no choice but to invite me this year, though,
because I came to Rome.
That's not the case at all.
I'm sure she's delighted to be able to spend her special day with you.
Claudio...
Hey.
Is nine o'clock OK for
Gabrielle's reservation?
That'll be fine, thank you.
I should get back.
Don't let anyone see you.
Thank you for preparing
the antipasto for me.
Oh, no. Claudio and Luciano were the ones behind that.
Oh, I see.
Ciao.
We'll be awaiting
your next visit.
She shouldn't even
come to the restaurant.
It's just going to
annoy Claudio.
Be more gentle
with the ingredients!
There are seven parties
booked for tonight.
One of them is a group
from Japan, so...
Claudio said he didn't feel
that way anymore, but...
That ring barely stays on.
Sure you haven't
lost weight, Claudio?
My fingers have
gotten narrower.
Why not just
take the ring off?
We've been through
this before, Vito.
It's because he can't
forget those memories.
That's not why...
Then what's the problem?
See, it's déjà vu.
It's not that he can't forget,
it's that he doesn't
want to forget, no?
Claudio!
Don't do that
like it's nothing!
Nicoletta!
Still, they sure are late...
May I interrupt?
Nicoletta!
Have a seat.
This is your dress
for the party.
I just finished
buying it for you.
Don't you have work?
I took the day off.
I'll get you
something to drink.
One cappuccino, please.
Should I give you two
a few minutes to talk?
I have to talk to you.
I thought that
might be the case.
Here you go, Nicoletta.
I think you know
how Claudio feels.
That's all in the past.
There's nothing to discuss now.
Maybe for you,
but not for Claudio.
And don't tell me
you haven't noticed.
Going to the restaurant all the time, even when you know how he feels, is downright cruel!
You're absolutely right.
I apologize.
Apologize to him.
OK.
But,
can I still come by
once in a while?
The food is just so good!
Everyone knows Nicoletta
has a crush on Claudio.
I feel bad for her.
Think about
Claudio's feelings, too.
Excuse me, guys...
Sorry.
It's all right.
Though,
you really should
take the ring off.
I'm starting to hate
myself for this.
Luciano is so blunt.
Claudio!
Gabrielle's on the phone.
I'm going to take a break from the restaurant for a while.
Did something happen?
Want to meet
and talk about it?
No, let's not.
That red-headed girl
stopped by earlier.
Nicoletta?
She said it to me...
That it's cruel for me to go to the restaurant when I know how you feel.
Sorry.
It's fine.
She's a good girl.
She really cares about you.
What's so wrong with
making Claudio some pasta?
Anyway, come try
this dress on!
What's that pot all about?
Nothing, really. I was just
in a cooking mood.
Claudio seemed
to really like it.
What?
He keeps a close
eye on you.
I think he was impressed at how you approached Gabrielle earlier.
That's my girl.
To think you grew up so well even with me not being around.
I really owe it to
your grandmother.
You're the worst.
Yeah, it's almost
spring here in Rome.
Is it still cold there, Grandma?
Yeah. But forget that,
I heard about Olga's birthday party coming up. You're going, huh?
It's so random.
She's never invited me before.
Just forgive her
and let it go.
She thought of you
in her own way.
She did?
Every year she'd send me a letter saying how sorry she was for not inviting you.
What are you going
to get her, Luciano?
You're gonna ask that and not say what you're getting her yourself?
Have a cup
of coffee, Claudio.
Oh, thank you.
What's that?
A list of those
invited to the party.
You're going to be
purely a guest tonight.
No way! I'm going to
be in the kitchen.
The Madam will be happier to see you attending as her daughter.
A daughter of a close
friend, remember?
Why does Claudio
know that?
You aren't wearing the
dress I picked out for you...
But I'm a staff member...
All the men are going to
be wearing suits tonight,
so I think it's OK if you
wear a formal dress.
Wearing a dress
in the kitchen?
Teo's not gonna like that.
No problem.
You'll take the day off!
It's a cozy party only for
close friends and family.
Then, she'll be
coming too, huh?
Hmm?
Gabrielle.
Doubtful.
I peeked at the menu before,
and it looks fantastic.
Go tell her
she should come.
She's your
good friend, right?
Ah, Nicoletta...
She's a good girl, isn't she?
Indeed.
Let's have a big party here
for her birthday too.
I'm always so busy
in November...
I've only ever been able to send a present and a card.
I'm glad she could
be here tonight.
Though, it'd be bad if others found out that she's my daughter.
What is it?
Your ring looks like
it's going to come off.
You should wear a different ring,
if it's just to keep the customers at bay.
I'll get one for you.
All right...
You make it so easy to take advantage of you, Claudio.
Well...
But you know, Claudio...
Yes?
Gabrielle isn't the only one
waiting for you to take that ring off.
Is my hair going to be
OK all flat like this?
Oh, whatever.
The pot!
It's like she just
cooked it for herself.
Actually, can she even cook?
I can't picture her
acting like a housewife...
I guess it's fine.
You look concerned
about me.
I'm not...
I won't say anything.
I'll the keep the fact
I'm your daughter a secret.
Happy birthday.
The food is a hit!
Isn't it fantastic?
Gigi's eating his fill tonight, even.
And we've got extra
help tonight, as well.
Oh no, I'm honored to be standing in the same kitchen as Mr. Facchini.
As you're a guest tonight,
you are not to enter the kitchen.
You don't have to block me...
He's blushing because you look so fetching tonight, Nicoletta.
What?
You're always quick
with the jokes!
But she truly is fetching.
Don't you agree, Claudio?
Absolutely.
Teo, it's about time we
bring her dish to the guests.
Carry it out, Nicoletta.
What? I-I shouldn't...
What? You're so
modest all of a sudden.
And here I was trying to pay
you your rightful dues.
Huh?
This is the best meal
you've made so far.
You did a proper job
and put feeling into it.
Show some
more confidence.
Guys...
Shouldn't you ask
someone else to do it today?
Is she really my daughter?
She's got it together so well.
Sure it's not because
you didn't raise her?
Seriously.
I've got to be one of
the worst mothers alive.
You were one.
But now, she's close by
and really looks to you.
A girl moving on from
her mother is a huge deal.
She's going to become a charming lady right by your side now, don't you think?
Tanti auguri a te.
Lorenzo?
Tanti auguri a Olga...
Tanti auguri a te.
My, it looks delicious!
Nicoletta made this cake
for you. She said it's a gift.
I have a confession to make.
My daughter, Nicoletta,
made this cake for me as a gift!
What?
I had her with
my ex-husband.
I apologize for keeping it
secret all this time.
I didn't want to be rejected,
so I just kept on lying...
I'm so sorry.
Oh, I knew.
What?
I knew she was your daughter
soon after she started working here.
You have the same smile.
I wondered why you
never said anything.
But, Lorenzo, you said you don't like women with kids...
Sure, I'd have preferred that.
But, I'll welcome her with open arms,
if she's your daughter.
I'm so sorry, Nicoletta.
It's fine.
I just get to be
a selfish brat for a while.
Anyway, blow out the candles!
Right...
Oh, I'll carry those.
Don't worry about it.
All right...
That was anticlimactic.
I didn't think the owner
was the type to reject her,
and turns out I was right.
But, I also understand what it's like to be a woman frantically in love and afraid of rejection.
I don't want to
be rejected either.
You're in luck, then.
I'm so happy.
Olga really seems like
she's made up for lost time.
It's like revealing her daughter has given her new life.
How are things
at the restaurant?
She's continuing on
as an apprentice.
Luciano still scolds her.
So, what did you
want to see me about?
Sorry it took so long.
Have you responded
to her feelings for you?
No, not yet.
Hmm?
We're still...
Come by the
restaurant sometime.
All right, here's a little extra.
Thank you.
Oh, Claudio!
Your father?
No way, my boyfriend.
Oh...
Nicoletta!
Sorry, she misspoke...
Are you out
shopping too, Claudio?
Yes. I'll carry your bags.
Thank you.
Anything else you
want to check out?
Claudio...
Are you free today?
I usually relax at home
on my days off.
Wanna come over?
I'll make you
something good to eat.
But...
All right. Carry those
bags to my apartment.
I wonder if the regulars will be able to tell we're an item.
I feel like I won somehow.
OK, smile.
Its name is casetta dell'orso.
If you ever find yourself
in Rome, go look for it...