What the hell is this?
And you call yourself a professional?
Some dreamy-eyed young apprentice would be more useful than an unmotivated bum like you.
What is it that you want to do?
Didn't you ever have a dream?
You're quitting?
That's why you were calling chefs from other restaurants.
I certainly can't count on you to do that.
Don't ever set foot in there again.
Are you still going to have a job here the next time I drop by?
Some stay and some go.
The restaurant holds people's histories within them.
Various personalities have mixed...
in this restaurant that sits on a corner of Rome.
So it's really broken?
I thought it felt a little cold in here.
When will it be fixed?
Tomorrow, at the earliest.
It could be until the following day.
If it's just one day, I think it'll be fine.
It's been pretty warm lately.
No, to be safe, we should close for the day.
I'll explain it to the customers who made reservations.
We can't have anyone catching a cold now.
Hey there.
Buon giorno.
Have you put some thought into the new menu?
You bet I did!
It looks like the market beat us to spring.
I'm delighted to be thinking up the new menu.
Say, I thought up a dish. If it's really good...
You want to see if it'll end up on the menu?
I remember.
But, I don't think that's gonna happen.
Oh, come on! We won't know until I try!
I know, I know.
I've got to start with the very basics.
Grilled scampi.
Veal sirloin.
Frittatas.
Buon appetito.
You know, if you kick the flavoring up a notch, I think it'll work.
I agree 100%.
If you marinated the meat a bit longer, and lightened up the sauce just a bit...
Guys, taste mine too!
With no further ado.
The presentation is nice...
...but it tastes like crap.
M-M-Maybe I overcooked the eggs...
You lack fundamentals.
Th-That's because you won't teach them to me!
Didn't you graduate culinary school?
Learn them on the job, by yourself.
Now, guys... There's no need to overcomplicate matters.
Well, you need to work on your plating!
Gigi plated it.
Wh-When did he...
Gigi, is the technician still going to be a while?
G-Gigi, you prefer more attractive plating, don't you?
All that matters is the taste.
Something smells delectable.
Claudio! Did you come to support me?
I wanted to see how the repairs are coming.
I'm glad we closed for the day.
It's freezing today.
Are you sure you didn't close because you can't stand a little cold?
A lady gets cold easily!
Claudio is just considerate of that.
Oh, right! Claudio!
Yes?
Come here!
Taste this.
Sure.
Well?
Well, it looks really nice.
Looks nice, huh?
Yes, but it looks really nice.
Looks nice...
This is delicious!
I'll get 'em this time!
I've been observing their techniques closely!
Pollo alla Diavola.
Artichoke in cream sauce.
Roasted lamb served with crispy potatoes.
Buon appetito.
Teo, you should use a little more salt.
Maybe it'll go better with porcini mushrooms.
Oh my... This is delicious!
How come they can make such delicious food?
They must have some secret in their arms!
It's not just their arms.
They both started to eat your dish, Nicoletta.
What?!
It's not bad...
It just defies sense.
S-Sure, maybe we can't serve it to the customers,
but maybe the staff could eat it, no?
Sure, but...
This is a ristorante!
This belongs in a mess hall!
It's too salty.
Sure it's just not to your tastes?
You aren't considering the customers at all.
I don't know what mess hall you trained in,
but this is a ristorante.
You need to relearn everything.
You can go straight to hell!
What's so bad about this dish?
The owner said it's good.
It's identical to the specialty at a restaurant I went to recently.
You're imagining things.
Quit making excuses and think up a new dish.
Screw her!
That is a letdown.
I wouldn't worry about it too much.
Teo just has a foul mouth.
We used to really worry about Teo too, back in the day.
Huh?
He was uninspired and always fighting with the head chef.
Teo?
Yeah.
He caused all sorts of headaches for us.
Why the culinary world?
I lived with my grandparents when I was a child.
I absolutely loved my grandmother's cooking.
How about you, Teo?
My father was a chef before he passed away.
What? In a ristorante?!
It was just a tiny osteria.
Did you ever cook for him?
Yes.
I bet he was thrilled at how delicious it was!
Sure, I guess.
Huh?
He wasn't a straight-shooter either.
In a ristorante back home...
In a two-star restaurant in Rome...
He trained for years and never improved.
He had the makings of a good chef, though.
I wanted to help him out somehow.
That's why I asked him to work in dell'orso.
I remember it well.
I bluntly told him that at least his dolces were good.
Teo used to want to show his father that he could make it.
But, he lost sight of his goals along with the passing of his father.
They say the master will appear when the pupil is ready, but...
I guess meeting lots of people is a great thing in itself.
Definitely.
Back when Teo and Vanna were going at it,
he was like a rebellious child!
Everyone starts off as an amateur.
I'll make them say it's delicious!
Make food that you like yourself.
Huh?
Is he talking to me?
Maybe I'll try some potatoes with cheese.
You're using bottarga!
What kind of fish?
Mullet.
It's because he grew up in Sardinia.
Oh, that's a nice area!
Bottarga, aragosta, Pecorino cheese...
Teo was brought up on rich ingredients from the mountains and the sea.
It was just a town out in the country.
The basis of a man's culinary tastes come from the type of food culture they were brought up in.
The wife and I talk about this all time.
One of these days, we want to have our own food tour of Italy.
That sounds like so much fun!
There's probably all sorts of good food in Italy.
There are ingredients we've never even heard of in different parts of the country.
I wouldn't mind traveling around on my motorcycle.
Of course, nothing tops Sardinia.
He hasn't really talked about it,
but I wonder if Teo has a special someone in his life.
He uses ingredients from back home...
I bet they make him think about his late father, too.
Make food that you like yourself.
I wonder how many years it's been since I made this.
Grandma!
This is incredible.
It's delicious!
Wrapping it in a pie crust... Furio never ceases to amaze.
Well then, next is Teo's dish.
How is it?
Delicious!
Absolutely delicious!
Nicoletta, you've said every plate is delicious so far.
I'd like a more delicate and rich response from a woman chef.
But, Nicoletta's facial expressions are more delicate and rich than words can convey.
I'd love you to try and top the old woman chef.
Woman chef? There used to be one here?
What?! I thought that was a man!
That's Vanna.
Teo and her were always going at it.
It was downright frightening.
So...
She ended up quitting because of him?
No, it was because of her family.
They moved to America.
She's a top-rate chef.
Up next is Nicoletta's dish.
I think this is the best I've made so far,
but...
Buon giorno!
I heard you're thinking up the spring menu?
It looks fabulous!
Buon appetito!
Delicious!
I can't get enough of that crispy pie crust!
This is lovely too.
Huh?
This tastes oddly... familiar...
Nicoletta.
This would be considered very good,
had it been made by a layperson.
However...
A pro can do better.
You're right.
Home cooking is good,
but it doesn't fly in a restaurant.
Thank you for being so honest with me.
Huh?
I learned an awful lot today!
Skills are important,
but I think it's also important to think about the people eating your dishes.
I think the next dish I make will be even more delicious!
I'll... go clean up.
She got a little full of herself.
Thank you.
There's a saying that us cameriere believe in.
Hmm?
A restaurant that serves good food to the staff is a good restaurant.
You even got Teo to honestly admit it was good.
I'm so glad!
Is it really OK for us to go home while the boiler is still being worked on?
We'll let Gigi worry about it, so it's fine.
It'll get even colder once night falls.
Indeed.
Huh? Isn't that Teo's motorcycle?
Did you figure out the menu?
Sure did.
Huh?
Long time no see.
It's been some time.
It sure has.
This is Vanna.
What?!
Ahh!
What's this all about?
You must be Nicoletta.
Piacere.
They told me you were in America.
I'm going back next week.
It's a shame you can't stay longer.
I'll come by to try out the new menu.
Please do!
I heard that you're a top-rate chef!
Who on earth said such a silly thing?
See you tomorrow.
Ciao.
Could those two be...
My wife's waiting at the enoteca.
Care to join us?
I have to go home and practice!
I had a tough time today.
You want to be acknowledged as being a good professional chef, don't you?
You called it!
Ciao!
You know, I'll think I'll take you up on that drink!
There's no reason for me to rush.
Right?
We'd love for you to join us.
Looks like I am without a rival.
Or am I mistaken?