After a fight, we go out for a good dinner.
We've been doing so since before we got married.
This is horrible.
People said the food was good, so my hopes were high,
but not a single dish was anything special.
Teo, people can hear you.
You think? I thought it was quite good.
You'd better rethink your definition of good.
Otherwise I won't let you prep the ingredients.
It does look like the chef has changed here.
I was hoping you could learn a thing or two, Nicoletta.
Oh well. 'Twas a waste of time.
It wasn't as bad as they said.
Sure, the quality dropped a little bit, but...
That wasn't your first time there?
Oh, that's right. I'm sure one of your midnight liaisons began there.
Weren't we going there to celebrate making up?
Yes.
But you're not out of the doghouse yet.
Gelato!
You want me to freeze?
If you ever find yourself in Rome, go look for it...
The mysterious ristorante full of bespectacled gentlemen.
This wine is pretty good.
Maybe I'll take another glass.
Sure, as soon as you finish that one.
Thanks.
I wish my husband would do these things for me.
An expensive wine is nice from time to time.
Can you recommend me something?
If you're looking for a recommendation...
Gigi.
What do you like?
He's a veteran sommelier.
Wow.
And your budget.
Umm...
I wouldn't give her a Tuscan red.
Perhaps a Piemonte? The recent whites have been selling well.
Oh, the Sardinians go well with seafood, too.
The whites from Le Marche go well with seafood pasta dishes.
Hey, Lucia.
Oh, Gianna, you're here too.
You know, yesterday I saw your husband with some woman.
Again? Once a playboy, always a playboy, huh?
He's always talking up the women at the store.
I'm OK with it as long he doesn't get serious.
Yeah, but it wasn't the first time I've seen him with a woman.
What?
And this was the same woman.
Man, it's freezing out there.
Oh, something smells great.
I rented us a DVD.
I saw a good movie the other day.
Oh yeah? What was it about?
About a husband who sneaks off to cheat on his wife and what she does afterwards.
Oh, I'm not talking about you.
I mean, you're just extra nice to girls.
It's not like you're cheating on me or anything.
So, there was this scene in the film.
The husband decides to come home for once.
The wife is hard at work at dinner. Suddenly she breaks a bottle of wine.
The shards of glass end up in the pasta, and the husband eats them.
She didn't do it on purpose, of course.
Then, the husband storms off, in a fit of rage.
That scene really left a deep impression in my mind.
You don't say?
Oh dear. I broke the wine bottle.
Don't worry. The shards didn't get in the pasta.
We have another bottle, anyway.
Oh, right.
I knew it. He has a mistress.
How long have you been married?
Two years. And we dated for two years before that.
He's been obsessed with women since back then.
And I don't mean that he was a serial dater.
He works as a salesman and picks up lots of women who come to his store.
But back then, he was just fooling around, right?
Yes. But this last discretion was the final straw.
My friend told me to see a specialist and sent me to you.
First, you'd divvy up your assets.
Then, a three-year legal separation.
After that, you can finally request a divorce.
What?
Getting divorced takes a lot of time and energy,
so please make sure you're properly prepared.
Oh, Furio's giving cooking lessons?
Yes. He said he runs them on his days off at the restaurant.
Well, do your best.
Say you will and I'll give you extra.
It's just some unsold things.
I will!
You can count on me!
I'll get really good at cooking and Teo will see me in a new light!
OK, today's lesson will be beef stew with polenta.
Are you ready?
Yes!
Well? Enjoying your first day?
You bet! It's a lot of fun and I'm learning a lot.
That's great.
Teach me lots, OK?
You got it.
Just who do you think you are?!
Furio belongs to all of us!
Wh-What? U-Uh... I'm sorry.
That was tough in there.
Most of the women are big fans of Furio.
Looks like it. And you're not, huh?
Yeah. I wouldn't really call myself a fan.
You're the new apprentice at the ristorante, right?
I heard about you from Vito.
Uh, umm...
I'm Marina, Vito's wife.
What?!
He's so used to haute cuisine,
so I'm coming here to get better at cooking.
Nice to meet you.
O-Oh, I see.
Man, was that a shocker!
She's no older than I am - Vito's wife.
But still, she's not uncomfortable?
Huh?
You know...
See?
Good point.
It wouldn't sit right with me.
I mean, Vito's really popular with the ladies,
and he's so much older than her.
Well, the only ones who know what goes on between a married couple is the husband and wife.
If it bothers you, why don't you ask Vito himself?
Wow, I'm honored.
To think you'd worry about us so much.
I'll leave it to your imagination.
For I worship all the women of the world.
I beg your pardon?!
Relax, relax.
Well, I can't help it if you're concerned.
But you know, I was the one who asked her out.
Seriously?
Yes.
It was a chance encounter of destiny, in the gym I used to go to.
'Twas love at first sight.
I was after her.
Then one day, there was a chance encounter at a karate dojo.
And then, thanks to a puzzle magazine I had in a broken elevator,
I was able to pop the question.
There you have it.
How much of that am I supposed to believe?
That's up to you, Nicoletta, dear.
God!
Another glass, please.
How about you tell her how you and Marina really got to know each other?
No, I cannot betray my wife's privacy.
A gentleman must harbor a secret or two, don't you agree?
Now that you mention it, the day you requested is coming soon, isn't it?
Indeed. I'm counting on you.
So I need to prepare myself for the divorce, huh?
He's all over the place, but it's not like I can't love him.
I mean, I do love him.
He just pisses me off. He really uses me.
I should fool around, too.
Buonasera.
We've got customers at table two.
Antipasto, please.
On it.
Put a little extra salt in the second course.
If I recall, her sister prefers a little stronger flavor.
Huh? Sister?
Yes.
You mean, Vito's sister?
Marina's sister.
She's visiting Marina while coming to see her folks.
Her husband is here, too.
Yeah?
Tonight, we've got a dish made with a yogurt marinade and tomato sauce...
Say, that's Marina's sister and her husband?
The husband, he's...
Yes, he's from another country.
They spend most of their time there.
Oh, I see.
The three of them used to live here, in town.
Eh?
But well, there's a long story, but eventually she stayed behind, alone, here in Rome.
When I first met her, Marina was still rough around the edges.
But, ever since her and Vito got married, she's had a smile on her face, like that.
Well, see you tomorrow. Ciao.
Ciao.
Should they be leaving Marina and them here?
Don't worry. The wife will catch up later.
Oh, thank you for before.
What?!
Huh?
Oh, there he is.
I couldn't get into my place.
I forgot the key and Lucia's not in.
So you got lonely and came here?
Did Lucia stop by?
She sure did, and she left with Gigi just a few minutes ago.
Kinda like somebody we know who leaves his wife to go fool around.
Who's Gigi?
Gigi, yeah... He's been a good man since the age of twenty-five.
He's really tall.
He might even be taller than me.
Plus he's a master sommelier and a gifted conversationalist.
There's not a woman who'd turn him down.
This is to pay you back for the advice you gave me. OK?
Are you always this quiet?
She got sick and tired of you cheating on her.
So why not go home with that blonde beauty?
Or whatever works for him, huh?
You think you're so smart.
Whatever.
If I had to wager a guess, it's because she was frustrated, and just...
I'll give you a glass on the house for being dumped.
Your wife is incredibly beautiful. Treat her well.
Huh?
You'd better listen to what your senior tells you.
The two of you have a lot in common when it comes to women.
Women just can't resist wanting to accompany me.
Right, right!
They just decide they want to join me for dinner and such.
Agreed. Which is why I never considered getting married.
I never wanted to hurt any one of them.
The girls knew what kind of guy I am,
so only the ones looking for a good time approached me.
When those women weren't around, I was completely alone.
But now, I've met my wife, whom I love.
Sometimes, I get to thinking...
What would the two of us be doing, had we never met?
I'm almost positive I'd be spending my days all alone.
If what I'm describing would make you feel lonely,
you'd better stop doing what you're doing.
And if you want to know about divorce, here's your guy.
No better person to tell you about it than a divorcee.
Oh, err... Umm... Nice to meet you.
You don't want to hear Lucia say she's leaving you, do you?
There's something you need to keep in mind if you want a long, healthy marriage.
Think hard about it.
She didn't come home again.
I can't survive alone.
But, I don't want to sit here all day waiting
for my wife to come home from a date either!
This is Friday night!
Leaving again, are we?
"Again"? You've been out partying yourself!
I'm allowed to go shopping with friends, aren't I?
It just ran a little late.
Sure you weren't out with some guy?
A guy named Gigi.
Gigi?
We had dinner the other night.
So you admit it!
He's an older man and cute when he ate.
He's older than my father, you know.
What?
How about you? Which hot little thing are you going out with today?
I was waiting for you to come home!
Dressed to go out?
Were you thinking about making things right with me?
Umm, I was thinking about what I need to do in order to have a long, healthy marriage.
I've been pondering the same thing, these last few days.
Did you figure it out?
I did.
But you need to stop having flings with random women.
That's the first step.
What did you come up with?
Th-The same thing.
I thought the same thing.
I made a reservation for dinner tonight, thinking we'd make up.
I was waiting for you to come home.
Please forgive me, Lucia.
I'll go get changed.
What?
Umm, the landlord called me. I wonder what it's about.
I'll be right back.
Get changed!
The one across the street... I've never set foot in there,
but I think I heard it's good.
A table!
Buonasera.
I can ready a table for you.
A couple just settled their tab.
Our top-notch sommelier, Gigi, will bring you an exquisite wine.
I believe he's already acquainted with your wife's tastes, so he can get started.
You are coming with your wife tonight, are you not?
This is a make-up dinner.
Please give us the best food and wine you can, for her sake.
Absolutely.
He was totally silent!
He never says a word!
That sommelier over there?
Yes!
But he sure picks a good wine.
Table five seems incredibly satisfied with dinner.
I think it's time for the dolce.
On it.
What's that? You two are oddly getting along all of a sudden.
Yeah.
No one charms the ladies like Vito.
Did he say some sweet things and sweep you off your feet?
Wouldn't you like to know?
I think I figured it out.
There's only one person he truly loves.
Vito.
Oh, you'll have to excuse me.
I'm afraid my lovely wife and I have plans for the rest of the day.
It's almost like we're on a date, huh?