These are the glasses
you'd wear for show?
A few years prior
Mr. Rizzo introduced you
to quite the restaurant.
But it looks like a nice place.
And I really like Claudio, the man who gave these glasses to me.
He's a real gentleman.
Claudio?
Furio,
I'd like to introduce you to someone sent here on the owner and the Madam's recommendation.
Sure thing.
I suppose I should
put these on, huh?
Yes, I think she'll like that.
Very well, then.
So? Have you gotten used
to the restaurant yet?
Yes, I certainly have.
This place has fewer staff than the other places I've worked, so I find it easier.
What about the fact so many aspiring chefs come here wanting to train
because they've heard
you're employed here?
Now, I don't know
about all that.
Just let me know if anything
ever bothers you.
I'm always available to talk to,
should you ever need to.
Speaking of these glasses...
Why is he so nice to me?
It looks to me that Claudio
knows you somehow.
That's the impression I got when
the owner first mentioned your name.
Seriously?
Those glasses look
fantastic on you.
So handsome.
You're too kind, Madam.
This is Furio.
He started as our
head chef last week.
What made you
choose dell'orso?
Well, it was on
Mr. Rizzo's recommendation.
He's so soft-spoken... Old Man Time has been kind to him.
I wish I could say
the same about myself.
He hasn't changed
a bit since then.
That was a few years ago.
This restaurant tucked
away in a corner of Rome
unknowingly provided me my second chance to work as a cameriere.
What's the matter?
Claudio...
Nicoletta broke
Furio's glasses.
They fell out of his breast pocket
when he bent over, and...
Snap.
I'm so sorry. I didn't look
where I was walking...
By the time I realized,
it was too late.
Don't apologize.
I was careless.
Don't worry about it. They'll be perfectly fine, once I fix them.
Since these were the keepsake that you so kindly gave to me, and all.
Thank you for
even considering that.
Wait, could those glasses be...
Yes, Claudio gave them as a gift to Furio when he first started here.
What?
I'm sorry, you two... Umm... I...
Don't worry about it.
Now hurry up
and pick the herbs.
Once you've done that,
you've got potatoes to peel.
Right on it, Chef.
Sheesh, she needs to stop behaving like such an amateur.
Everyone's an amateur
when they first start.
Try and look at
the big picture.
Oh, right. Angela said she
wants to stop by tonight.
Think you can keep
a table open for her?
Sure. I'm pretty sure
we had a cancellation.
If you'd like, I can
prepare her usual table.
Grazie.
Is she coming alone? Or...
It sounds like she's coming
with some old friends.
She said it'll be
a party of three.
Oh, and my wife requested
you as her server.
I don't mind.
Then it's a deal.
Back to work.
All right...
When I am gonna stop
making so many mistakes?
Don't beat yourself up.
I'm on dish-washing
duty every night.
They don't even let me
cook food for the staff.
I can teach you how to make a mean cup of espresso.
Thank you.
I bet you never had to worry
about this stuff, huh?
No, they were much harsher on me when I was starting out.
I should have
expected that answer.
If that's true, then how
did you get so used to it?
That's a fine question.
You're mean.
That's the spirit.
Buonasera, Angela.
Buonasera, Claudio.
Did you escape the rain?
Come, follow me.
Take good care
of us tonight, okay?
I'm glad that
you'll be our server.
Th-Thank you.
He's a fan of my husband.
Treat him kindly,
would you?
Very well, Madam.
That was cruel, Furio.
You didn't mention
he'd be here.
Why, whatever do you mean?
Okay, this is done.
Please take it out there.
I don't see
your hands moving!
Get the next plate ready.
Oh, right.
I'm so sorry!
Damn it. Focus on your work!
Time flies.
Has it really been over
twenty years already?
The good old days...
I deeply apologize.
Claudio!
Back off.
I'm sincerely sorry
about that, Madam.
I can't believe he'd do such a thing to Mrs. Rossi,
one of this hotel's best patrons.
All is forgiven.
Claudio, Mrs. Rossi, from before, has asked you to come to her room.
She's in room 1201.
But, sir...
Go and get your
tongue lashing.
Ma'am, I sincerely
apologize for before.
Stop apologizing.
Relax.
Since I can't very well have them dock your pay to cover the dress...
Excuse me, Madam...
The restaurant is quite
busy at this hour.
I have to get back to work...
I see. Then we'll have
to make this quick.
I can't.
Madam, please stop...
A cameriere can't
tell me what to do.
You are to pleasure me.
Both tonight
and in the future.
What do you
have to say to that?
Very well, ma'am.
Don't just stand there, Claudio!
Put these dishes away!
Oh... Yes, sir.
I-I'm sorry.
You're completely
useless, Mr. Santo.
I can smell the woman's
perfume on you.
Are you in paradise,
Mr. Paradiso?
I'm not feeling well.
I haven't eaten since yesterday.
They made me do chores
and threw my meal away.
No, no! Don't use
lemon, use pepper!
You got a fever
or something?
No, I'm just feeling weak
since I haven't eaten.
What was that
chef's name again?
Hey.
Eat it.
Let me taste it.
Me too.
That's good.
Furio is really something.
He's the head chef here
at such a young age.
And I heard he's being flooded with catering requests, too.
Wow...
He's amazing.
He's younger than I am and yet he's made such a name for himself.
He's well respected, too.
Maybe I should give up
on this cameriere thing.
Should I quit
being a cameriere?
Though I've only been
at it a few weeks.
I feel bad watching you
eat while standing.
Why don't you sit down?
I'll forgive you for it.
A regular?
I'm actually not hungry.
What a waste of such
scrumptious-looking food.
You're new, aren't you?
I've never seen you before.
What's your name?
Claudio.
Your full name.
Santo Claudio
Paradiso.
That's a fine name.
What?
No, it's just...
I often get teased
for my name.
That blows.
But I'm sure it's not
just because of the name.
You look like you're begging
to be picked on.
Sorry for being so blunt.
You're right. I desperately want to change my personality.
I've even begun to think I might not be cut out to be a cameriere...
I realized that while
watching Furio, the chef here.
He's so amazing.
I don't think I'll ever
get to be like him...
Being a chef and being a cameriere are two different things.
Right. Of course.
Why did you decide to become a cameriere? Just for the hell of it?
I think that bringing food to customers, who are so looking forward to dining, is a wonderful thing.
Furio is Furio. You are you.
Why not just do what you feel
is a wonderful thing?
You have no reason to be
bothered so much by it.
If it really bothers you,
find a new place.
There are lots of employees here with plenty of connections elsewhere.
Why not find
a new restaurant?
A restaurant that suits you.
My name is Angela,
Santo Claudio.
Ciao.
Would you like me
to call Furio out?
Please.
Who's that girl?
Oh, that's the daughter
of the owner of this hotel.
She's engaged to Furio.
It's as if my heart was
broken twice in one day.
Here's your dolce.
Thank you.
I'm very impressed with Furio.
You can tell he's
gotten better with age.
Right?
And you camerieres
are all so refined...
Though, I am curious about why you're all wearing spectacles.
But you can tell Furio
chose a great restaurant.
Thank you very much.
Pardon me asking, but where did you do your apprenticeship?
Well... I started off
in a hotel ristorante.
You don't say?
I used to manage a hotel that Angela's father owned.
Fascinating.
Where'd you go from there?
Well, I moved
from here to there,
and then spent about twenty years in a small restaurant in the suburbs.
I actually worked alongside him there, believe it or not.
You don't say.
It must have been
quite the establishment.
But I wish I had you
on our staff at the hotel.
Yes, go and call
Furio out here.
I'd definitely like
to speak to him tonight.
We can share old battle
stories from the hotel.
Weren't you
surprised to see him?
He said he was coming to visit me after all these years,
so I figured we
had to come here.
I know. I almost said something about it when I saw you guys.
Sorry about that. Angela asked me to stay quiet about it.
Even so, your old boss
didn't recognize you at all.
I suppose I should have
screwed something up!
You know, break a
plate or something.
You should have!
Please. You didn't remember him when you saw him, either.
Oh, yeah... So many people came through that hotel's doors, so...
No, I was only
there a short time.
I was amazed you
remembered me at all.
I never forget a face,
even if we only
meet for a moment.
Besides, we talked to each other back then, remember?
I remember it well.
Also, your mood hadn't
changed a bit then.
I was always so
worn and haggered,
until I came here.
I thought I told you not to
worry about those things.
Did you find a good
restaurant to work at?
I did.
That was fantastic.
Oh, Claudio.
Wh-What's wrong?
Actually, Teo said that since we're going to be thinking up a spring menu,
I should think of a dish
to serve the staff!
Congratulations.
That's fantastic news.
She can't stay
an amateur forever.
I'll try to not be too
critical of you, though.
I feel rejuvenated somehow!
Like I have to get to work
on this right away!
Good luck.
Thanks. Look forward to it.
Oh, if it's all right, could you taste it before I show it to him?
Sure. I'd be happy to.
See you tomorrow, then. Ciao!
I lost some things along the way, but I met many new faces, as well.
Somehow the sands of time
have brought me here, to dell'orso.
Now, to me anyway,
this restaurant is the happy
place that calms my soul.
The presentation is nice...
...but it tastes like crap.
M-M-Maybe
I overcooked the eggs...
You lack fundamentals.