I heard from Mr. Rizzo that
the chef here is quite talented.
Sorry for the wait.
This is tonight's
antipasto misto.
Please take your
time to savor it.
See? It looks delicious.
Indeed.
What's wrong?
Nothing...
Waiter!
Yes, sir?
Why do all the employees
here wear spectacles?
Well, that's this
restaurant's trademark.
Huh?
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
What are those?
Oh, those are photographs taken when this restaurant opened.
The staff has changed
a little since then.
That man wasn't
wearing spectacles.
Yes, that's why he left.
Wait, he was fired?!
Of course not.
That's not grounds for that.
But the owner
is a curious one.
It's one thing to have a wife who likes bespectacled gentlemen, it's another to open a place like this.
Well, anyway, this wine
is truly delectable, Gigi.
He treats his wife
like a goddess.
She truly met a wonderful man to make her husband.
Look at her,
smiling like that...
Are you not feeling well?
No, no!
Feel free to speak your
mind about anything.
If you're a friend of the Madam,
you're a friend of ours.
Thank you.
I will do just that.
Man... Now I can't tell them
I'm really her daughter.
Yeah, it's really
comfortable living here.
She's taking care of all
my living expenses.
Though she did break her
promise to meet and talk.
Well, she is really busy.
Hey, Grandma...
There's a guy I really like.
But I can't tell if
it's love or what...
I'm not really good at talking about these sorts of things.
Why don't you talk to Olga?
She's your mother, plus you're all the way there, in Rome.
My grandmother was the one who suggested I go to Rome.
I know it's because she wanted me to make up with her.
I get that she's busy.
Well, if I'm staying
here in Rome,
I should probably
look for a job.
But, what sort of job
should I look for?
I just moved here without
thinking things through.
They're closed today.
Lovely.
Shall we go get
some food, Francesco?
Sure, Grandpa.
How about
that panini place?
I wonder if they
have my usual.
Hmm?
What's that?
Hey!
Luciano!
Nonno, who's she?
She's a friend of
the owner's wife.
For some reason, she's been coming to eat with the staff every day at the restaurant.
Your grandson?
I'm Francesco.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Nicoletta.
Don't believe everything your grandfather says about me.
Are you hungry?
Oh, it's Gigi!
Buon giorno.
Are you always
on this bench?
Sheesh... Why can't they just let me relax on my day off?
Put that all in, too.
We'll add in salt and pepper.
You're good
at cooking, miss.
It's because I used to help my grandma cook since I was about your age.
Your grandma?
Not your mother?
That's right. I learned how to cook from my grandma.
Wow...
Buono!
Well? Change your
mind about me at all?
Not bad, for an amateur.
I like it.
He spoke.
How long are you in town?
Planning to stay
in Rome forever?
I don't think I could.
What do your parents
say about this?
My daddy's always
taking business trips.
Oh, that must be tough.
In any case, look for a job.
You can't just
be here for fun.
You've got to
take it seriously—
Save the speech,
I'm already looking!
Looking!
Don't copy me!
Don't copy her!
OK!
Claudio's not coming today?
Maybe, since it's his day off, he's treating his wife and kids!
No?
Hey!
Wow, this pasta
is actually edible.
What was that all about?
Sounds like Nicoletta is spending a lot of time at the restaurant.
You never know what to expect from her. She's still a kid.
Why don't you invite
her over sometime?
Since she's your
friend and all.
To be honest, I don't know
how to connect to her.
In my mind, she's still that little girl I knew years ago.
Just treat her normally.
Don't worry so much.
It's not like you.
Thank you.
What's with Luciano?
He treats me like a little kid.
Though it's true, I've never really thought about my future.
I really should think
about my future.
But, for the time being,
love is just as important!
Buon giorno, Nicoletta.
Buon giorno.
Is this love?
I really don't know yet.
You again?
Like this Luciano guy who
does nothing but complain...
I'll walk you home.
If he suddenly became really kind to me, would I fall in love with him over that?
They said it wasn't
gonna rain today...
Shall I call you a cab?
I'll be fine if I run!
I'd be fine doing that, but you...
Use it. You'll both fit.
Thanks.
Thank you, Luciano.
I'm loaning it to Claudio.
Now take her home before
the sky really opens up!
What a nice guy.
Isn't he?
That's true. Gigi is
somewhat strange.
But he's a good guy, too.
What's your
wife like, Claudio?
I don't have one, actually.
But... that ring...
There's a reason I wear this.
There are some customers who try and pursue me for real.
They'll start talking about
marriage and the like.
So, this is a countermeasure
against that.
My wife and I
separated years ago.
What should I do?
He opened up to me.
I hate the whole
idea of adultery.
I'd never bring up the
idea of marriage, though...
My wife and I
separated years ago.
There are some customers who try and pursue me for real.
So, this is a countermeasure
against that.
Here you go.
Uh, umm...
Have a seat.
OK.
Thank you very much.
My...
This smells lovely.
What is it?
I bought it at a shop nearby.
I see.
What should I do?
I can't take my
eyes off of him.
He's so much older than I am... I've never felt like this before.
Umm...
I want to try and see
if this is all right or not.
I know I like you,
but I can't tell if it's real...
Hold on a second...
Umm...
I mustn't.
I think... he's a real gentleman.
Nicoletta, it's been a while!
I brought you
some chocolates!
Keep your hands
off my Claudio.
Why's he yours?!
All the gentlemen
there belong to me.
I'm truly sorry for being in your friend's apartment at such a late hour.
It's fine. Have a seat.
I know that she dragged
you here against your will.
No, but...
I'll let the two of you talk.
Ah... All right.
You're not serious, are you?
You're serious?
Yes. I'm single,
so who cares!
Then why not go
after Luciano? He's single!
Why?
Then, Teo?
What is this? It's like you don't want me going after Claudio for some reason.
Well... I understand, but Claudio doesn't know how to handle a woman's advances.
Say, why don't you move back to your grandmother's?
What the hell?!
You're young. There's no
need to rush things.
You should focus on
getting a job, and your future.
Enough! Why does everyone treat me like a little kid?
Huh?
I've thought about
all that already!
But I don't know
what I should do!
I don't know
what I'd be good at.
You're good
at cooking, miss.
Hey, why'd you go
quiet all of a sudden?
Hey, I have a favor to ask.
Huh?
If you help me out, I'll reconsider telling your husband that I'm your daughter.
I'm Nicoletta and I'll be working as an apprentice here, starting today.
I look forward to
working with you.
Since Lorenzo
said it was fine,
it's OK with me.
But promise me you
won't leave the kitchen.
Of course not!
So you've always had
an interest in cooking, huh?
They said you even went
to cooking school for a bit.
Yes, but I had never
thought about it as a career.
So what made you
change your mind?
I couldn't figure out
what I wanted to do,
but I knew I wanted
to be independent.
I plan on using this opportunity to learn everything I can about cooking.
Excellent.
Say, you give cooking classes at your home, don't you?
Can I join in?
I'd love that.
Man, there's no pancetta.
Giuseppe swore up and
down he'd get it, too...
That's no good. We can call,
but it takes them a while to deliver it.
How about I go and get it?
Just tell me where to go.
Claudio. You heard her.
Please escort her there.
Umm...
Sorry about last night,
for doing that to you.
But, I want to let you
know that I'm serious.
I don't regret what I did.
It's fine. I'll lay off a bit.
Nicoletta, I...
I'm serious about
learning how to cook.
I didn't start working at the restaurant just because of you.
I want to try and pursue something I may be good at.
I don't want to
always depend on Olga.
I want to be truly
independent someday.
Then, I'll become a great woman,
and get back at her!
I've had enough of people
treating me like a kid!
Please give it your all.
I'll support you.
Sure. I can use your
support more than ever!
Ladies first.
Thank you.
It's so great to be working
in the same place as him!
Gabrielle's coming tonight, right?
I'll have to make
a really grand dolce, then.
Gabrielle? Could that
be someone special?
Buonasera.
Gabrielle is here.
Got it.
Hey, is Gabrielle
a VIP or something?
Yes. She's Claudio's ex-wife.
I wanna see!
Stay out of sight.
She has such beautiful skin.
That's his ex-wife?
Yes.
Well, it is his "ex"-wife.
Good work today, Nicoletta.
See you tomorrow!
When are you going to
stop wearing that ring?
I won't order you
to do it, though.
Anyway, see you later.
I'm sorry I interrupted
your conversation.
Nothing of the sort.
Claudio...
Could he still have
feelings for his ex-wife?
The restaurant is located
on a street in Rome.
Its name is casetta dell'orso.
She's my mother.
I said it.
What?!