I had fun last night.
When can I see you again?
Why aren’t you
saying anything?
Would you look
me in the eyes?
How long are you
going to wear that ring?
I get it. You still have
feelings for her.
You said all those nice
things to me. It’s not fair.
You invited me.
Now hold on a second.
We’ll be awaiting
your next visit.
Buona notte.
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
Well? Gotten used to
the restaurant yet?
Absolutely. I mean, Vito, Luciano,
and all of you have been so kind to me…
Furio! Teo!
Not often I see you with a young lady in tow. A new staff member?
This is Nicoletta.
She’s apprenticing with us.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise. And I appreciate
your patronage.
This is Mauro.
He owns this stand.
I always try to come here when we need vegetables, in between deliveries.
He’s always got some
unique things for sale.
I can see that.
Have any puntarelle?
We been sold out for hours. What time do you think it is?
Sheesh, I was just asking.
Hey, I told you
not to do that!
Say, do you have
a girlfriend, Teo?
Depends who’s
asking, I suppose.
What does that mean?
He’s just shy.
Must be nice…
That daughter of mine… Looks like she’s got a crush on Claudio.
Seriously?
The one with the red hair, right? I saw her at the restaurant.
But I’m not surprised to hear she did, considering she’s your daughter.
Daughter?
A good friend of mine’s daughter.
I treat her like my own.
Really now?
Oh, I think I heard about her.
Huh?
I was talking to Claudio about his wedding ring and when he’s gonna take it off.
She may have gotten
the wrong idea.
There’s nothing wrong
about it, Gabrielle.
Did he say he’s still
in love with me?
That’s decidedly
untrue, Olga.
He may have had feelings for me when we broke up,
but now it’s only because he missed his chance to lose the ring.
Now he’s stuck in
a holding pattern.
Olga, you’ve got a client.
Your afternoon schedule
is packed, so please hurry!
Fine, fine.
Anyway, let her be.
It’ll do her well.
She still has lots to learn…
Another divorce case today?
I’m so sick of them…
Why do relationships
have to be so complicated?
Olga!
Be right there!
It’s tough to be
a sought-after attorney.
Season the vegetables.
But don’t put so much in as to taint the color of the ravioli.
We’re going to serve this as the staff meal, but do you want to try it?
She seems a bit
down today, huh?
Claudio.
She’s depressed.
Uh, wait, Luciano?
It’s because Gabrielle
came by, I bet.
Even if she’s your ex-wife.
I know it bothers her. Everyone knows she started working here because she has a thing for you.
It’s all fine and dandy if you want to date a young girl like Vito does,
but if you don’t,
stop being so kind to her.
Don’t get her hopes up.
Tonight was another
splendid dinner.
Here’s a little token
of my gratitude.
Thank you very much.
I can’t make it next week,
unfortunately.
I finally got tickets to the opera in Milan, so I’ll be going there.
Oh, Santa Lucia!
Table five is ready
for their primo course.
Sure thing.
Maybe it’s my imagination, but he’s been avoiding looking at me since that night.
Nicoletta, stop daydreaming.
Oh, right.
Night, guys.
It’s my treat. Let’s have a glass of wine at the enoteca.
Sorry, I have
something to get to.
Sorry to hear that.
I’ll take a rain check.
Is he avoiding me after all?
That’s quite the bargain, Gigi.
What do you say,
a hundred Euro?
You’re breaking
my balls, man.
Guess it’s a deal.
I’ve been looking
for this one.
What? Your wife is
really that young, Vito?!
Yes, she’s still in college.
Really?
I met her at my old gym.
I was the one who
approached her.
A couple of exercise
freaks, those two.
Be careful when you’re with him,
unless you like muscle pain.
So, what’s it like being married to someone so much younger than you?
I don’t really think about it.
Every day is a lot
of fun, to be honest.
You don’t say.
Say, Vito… Claudio’s ex—
Buonasera.
Angela, you’re late.
Who’s that?
Furio’s wife.
That’s her.
You’re Nicoletta, right?
My husband told
me about you.
I’m Angela.
Pleasure to meet you.
O-Oh, likewise.
So, how’s the wine?
Good.
Yes, I think
I’ll have the same.
You got it.
This is my lovely bride.
I see…
Everyone looks so happy.
Good night. I’ll call you.
Oh, hi.
Long day at work?
Yeah, exactly.
I had dinner with a couple
who are a client of mine.
My shoulders
are all stiff now.
Say, want to have
a glass of wine over there?
Maybe next time.
I’ll swing by the restaurant
sometime then.
Ciao.
You’re late.
Where the heck were
you off gallivanting?
Delinquent girl.
What’s with
all these clothes?
They’re all yours.
You just bought
me some clothes.
I was out shopping
and couldn’t resist.
What about work?
My afternoon was free,
what can I say?
Okay, I’ll go put some tea on.
You met Gabrielle, right?
H-Huh?
She’s a close friend of mine.
I told you to lay off Claudio,
right? About that…
I won’t say anything
if you’re serious about him.
Thank you.
You’re welcome.
So? Are you?
I can’t tell if my
feelings are real or not.
But I do think…
Yeah, he’s special.
I’m happy when
he’s around,
and I can’t take
my eyes off him.
That’s love.
Your mind is filled with
thoughts of him. I get it.
That’s the most
exciting time.
You’ve got the real thing,
so be confident about it.
But, I…
As your mother, I should be telling you to date someone your own age.
However, as a fellow woman,
I want to say that love knows no age.
But Claudio’s a tough one,
so I don’t think it’ll be easy for you.
The other night, I thought that maybe he still has feelings for her.
Yeah, that might be true.
But he just wears that ring
to keep the customers at bay.
Hey, what was it like when you fell in love with the owner?
Love at first sight.
What?
Was he really slender
and intelligent-looking?
Nope. He hasn’t
changed a bit.
He looked like a bear. I fell in love the first time I laid eyes on him.
Was he wearing glasses?
He’s got 20/20 vision.
Don’t you have
a spectacles-fetish?
Big time.
So when he was
opening the restaurant,
I made him promise to have all the employees wear spectacles.
Isn’t he such a sweetheart?
I screwed up once, so I vowed not to fall in love,
and tried to focus exclusively on work.
But once I fall for
someone, I’m hopeless.
I fall head over heels.
He proposed to me, though.
But he was dead set on not marrying a woman with a child.
That’s why I had to
keep you a secret.
Sorry about that.
He scared me the
other day, though.
He’s got a pretty keen
sense of intuition.
Looking at her…
I’m envious, and I feel
kinda depressed.
Let’s see…
Porro and broccoli…
You opened another
expensive bottle of wine, Gigi.
Every day. Because the
owner doesn’t notice.
Hey, I’m not gonna complain about being able to drink good wine.
You said it.
Indeed.
Good food calls
for good wine.
Dinner’s ready.
A-Ah?
I’ll help you.
Just let me know if
anything’s bothering you.
I know this might seem
strange of me to say.
Umm, you’ve been acting a little odd ever since Gabrielle stopped by.
Y-Yeah, but that’s not what
I was thinking about right now.
Hmm?
Claudio, you don’t have to go out of your way to be nice to me.
I overstepped
my boundaries.
Luciano said
the same thing.
That I’m bothering you, huh?
No, just that it’s rude to be kind to you if it’s not genuine.
So what were
you thinking about?
That I’m jealous
of the owner’s wife.
As a fellow woman, that is.
She’s got both her work-life and love-life under control.
Everyone here likes her too.
I think you’ve got a lot in common with her, though…
You’re both straightforward and empowered. But also…
She’s my mother.
I said it.
What?!
Keep that a secret.
The owner
doesn’t know either.
I actually planned on telling him when I came here, though.
She dumped me at my grandmother’s
when I was a little girl.
She never cared
for me much.
And it was all so she
could marry the owner.
But, it’s also because
she got busy with work.
I get the fact that her work kept her from caring for me until now.
On the other hand, it pisses me off.
Forcing me into this situation.
I feel both jealous
of her full lifestyle
and even more pissed off.
My ex-wife works in
the same office as her.
Really?
She got busy with work
as well and we were fighting.
And that’s why
you split up?
We tried to talk about it
and ended up divorced.
We’ve got a lot
in common, us two.
In that we were
both cast aside?
I understand how you feel.
Back when we were still together, I could tell from the look on her face how full her life was.
Seeing her like that made
me feel a little uneasy.
If you ever have any questions,
just let me know.
I’m not sure how much I can bring to the conversation,
but if you ever need
someone to vent to…
You’re such a
nice guy, Claudio.
Are you like
this to everyone?
In the spirit of
full disclosure…
My real name is…
Santo Claudio Paradiso.
Paradiso?
Santo Claudio Paradiso…
Yes. As a child, I was often
made fun of because of it.
No, it means “heaven”! What better name could you ask for?
You can talk to me
whenever you want.
Thank you.
He really does
seem like a saint.
You work too much.
After you’re discharged tomorrow,
want to stop for a drink on the way home?
You know, at the place
where he works.
Sure.