Excuse me…
I’m sorry. I often see
you here, so I just…
My father is buried here.
Sorry to be rude,
but may I ask your name?
You must have lost someone
very dear to you.
Excuse—
Come on,
we’re ready to leave.
We have to mail out
all the invitations today.
This mysterious restaurant is on a road just a little ways from the center of Rome.
Buonasera.
We’ve been expecting you.
He’s here!
Mr. Rizzo, a regular,
promised to bring him here!
Senator Fassone…
He… He’s gorgeous!
Sheesh. Just when I was starting to think better of her, she acts like that?
It sure is nice to see
the Madam in good spirits.
If you say so.
Oh, Nicoletta.
The owner is in the back.
Take this to him.
S-Sure.
I still don’t get her
obsession with gentlemen.
Here you go.
Thank you.
You used to the place yet?
Yes, definitely.
The owner really
does look so kind…
“Why Olga of all people?”
…et cetera, is what
I’d like to ask him.
Come to think of it, I’ve never really talked to Gigi either.
But I don’t think he
dislikes me or anything…
He tipped me off on how
to sneak in free dolces…
What a peculiar man.
I can’t get a read on him.
I heard he was
born in the north.
Mr. Fassone must be tired from working in the Senate.
So how about…
Can’t we give him something, on the house, to let him relax?
A Piemonte red.
I picked it up on
my last day off.
It’ll go very well
with his primo course.
That’s the one!
I knew you’d come through!
You just keep doing
whatever you want, don’t you?
Some might call that
abuse of power.
Whatever do you mean?
No matter how much you like
bespectacled men, that’s just playing favorites!
It’s not playing favorites!
As the proprietress of this establishment,
it’s my duty to see that our customers are satisfied.
And also…
Follow me.
See? Gigi’s a real pro.
Without you saying a word, he’ll pick the exact wine that you’re craving.
Nicoletta, when you’re done with that, bring the owner’s dishes back here.
His next course
is about ready.
Okay.
He comes to refill his glass even though he can’t see him drinking it.
He knows the pace
I normally drink at.
Have you known
Gigi a long time?
If I recall, he’s been
here since the start…
Yeah. Look at the second
picture from the right.
That was taken
twenty-seven years ago.
You’re so young!
That was taken when my brother and I opened the ristorante next to the winery.
The precursor to this place.
What?!
I manage a winery.
I-I knew that.
The two of you are brothers?
Yeah.
Half-brothers.
Oh… No wonder you’ve
known each other so long.
Exactly.
But we met when
I was twenty-three.
Yes, I remember it well.
A wine connoisseur
that I knew introduced us.
I was visiting a home
in the suburbs of Turin.
Gian Luigi Orsini…
Huh?
My big brother?
Right. My father
told me about you.
Nice to meet you, big bro.
What are you
running off for?
Did I do something?
My father says
we aren’t to meet.
Wait. You’re brothers,
but you weren’t allowed to meet?
Gigi and I share
the same mother.
My father managed
a winery outside of Rome.
Gigi’s father was a successful businessman in his hometown of Turin.
So, I was born here and
Gigi was born over here.
I see…
But that’s not all.
These two are
actually brothers, you see.
So to me, he’s both my half-older brother and my cousin.
So you mean…
Exactly. My father slept with his older brother’s wife.
And then, I was born.
It’s surprising.
I didn’t expect you to have such an interest in politics.
Of course, you are
a talented lawyer,
so I suppose I shouldn’t
have assumed otherwise.
Table four is asking
for the check.
Oh, sure thing.
What a fascinating restaurant,
staffed by nothing
but men in spectacles!
This was actually a gift the owner made to his beloved wife.
Yes, I’m blessed to have met such a wonderful husband.
Indeed.
Thank you.
Umm, so your mother, she…
Yes, she passed away.
Well before Gigi
and I ever met.
My uncle never forgave
my father for what he did.
He said that by sleeping with his own brother’s wife, he severed all familial ties.
He cut all ties with me, that stupid older brother of mine.
But it’s all true.
Seems he’s a sommelier.
That’s what was on his business card.
Gigi, really? I see.
I’m going to stop by the restaurant where he works, Dad.
Then, I have
a favor to ask you.
Hey there, big bro.
My dad has
a message for you.
“Stop by anytime for a drink.”
Look how you’ve grown.
Seems he took
a liking to our winery.
He soon started
coming there alone.
He was a real character,
back then.
I started to like him myself.
What a waste.
I had a brother like you all these years,
and yet we spent them apart.
I wish I had met you earlier.
We’re not involved
in our fathers’ feud,
so let’s stay on
good terms, Gigi.
My father and I
talked the other day.
We tossed around the idea of opening a fun, little ristorante next door,
to go along with
the wine we’re making.
If you’d be willing,
I could use your help,
in making the wine list.
This is an outrage!
I made it very clear that you were not to meet with people from that household!
Don’t you dare get
near him ever again!
Dad.
What?!
I’ve made up my mind to work in the ristorante that Lorenzo is opening.
Over my dead body!
I’ve made up my mind.
You may have your feud,
but it’s got nothing to do with us.
The only wine we drink
is from Piemonte!
Lorenzo’s wines
are just as good.
Gigi!
Apparently, my uncle
always had a weak heart.
Gigi asked their servant
to confirm that he’s dead,
and then called the police.
I… killed my father.
Well, yeah…
Hearing the circumstances, it sounds like an accident.
But we still need to ask
him if he killed him.
So I figured we’ll let him spend the night in jail, then take him home tomorrow.
And then, we opened
the ristorante a year later.
Those were some times.
Pardon me.
It’s lasagna.
Thanks.
Teo commented that
you’ve been gone a while.
Please excuse me.
Sure.
Was he telling
you about Gigi?
Yes. I’m so surprised.
I had no idea he was
the owner’s brother.
Gigi does the books
every night, too.
The owner operates the winery too, so he’s quite busy.
Oh, that’s why…
He’s eating a lot today.
He eats too much.
Though, I don’t think he does whatever he wants because they’re brothers.
I think he’d be like that
no matter where he was.
The owner’s story
makes me feel that way.
I agree.
Grazie. I’ll be back.
Ciao!
The Senator
seemed satisfied!
He might come
back someday!
It was nothing.
I was just doing my job.
But this might get us
some good publicity.
And not for the spectacles,
but for the food.
No, no… Furio’s cooking and Teo’s dolces
are already well-known in town…
You don’t believe that, do you?
But anyway,
thanks, you guys!
The food was
delicious today, as usual!
Oh, no. Just the fact you
eat it is thanks enough.
Look, Mommy really wants to get married to someone,
but he told me he won’t get married to someone who’s been divorced.
So you understand, right?
I think I understand why
the owner opposes that.
His parents were like that…
And two brothers with the same woman… I’d better stop this train of thought.
He just doesn’t want the
same thing to happen again.
That label… That bottle’s from the owner’s winery, isn’t it?
For me?
It’s delicious!
It’s an ‘82. The year
the ristorante opened.
Ma’am, you have a
phone call from Mr. Rizzo.
Oh!
Grazie! Thanks for tonight!
Oh, right. I wanted to tell
you what happened…
She sure is a lively one.
You’re her daughter,
aren’t you?
Claudio wouldn’t
have told him…
Why do you say that?
We don’t look alike at all.
You share the same smile.
Yeah! Exactly!
Okay, I’ll be waiting for you.
Ciao!
He knows what wine people want to drink
because he observes them closely.
Two brothers going
after the same woman…
Love takes all shapes
and sizes, I guess.
Buonasera.
Hey, the Senator
stopped by, didn’t he?
How did Olga react?
You know an
awful lot, don’t you?
She couldn’t stop talking about it
back in the office. It was nuts.
Gabrielle? You’re late!
What were you
doing all night?
Come on, sit down!
So yeah, the Senator
just left a little while ago,
but he was
drop-dead gorgeous!
Congratulations!
I hope you have
a happy marriage!
Congratulations!
Hi. I’m sorry
about the other day.
We’re going to live
together in Palermo.
So, I don’t think you’ll
see me there very often.
How does she
know this man?
I see him quite a bit. Whenever we’re visiting the cemetery.
I don’t want
my father to be lonely,
but am I being a bad daughter for moving so far away?
Not at all.
I’m sure he’s happy for you,
up in heaven.
Thank you.
I wish a life of eternal
happiness for you as well.
I should be able
to have fun, too.
The girls know
what kind of guy I am,
so only the ones looking for a good time approach me.
When those women weren’t around,
I was completely alone.
But now, I…